<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mac on Nushan Kodikara</title>
    <link>https://www.nushankodikara.com/tags/mac/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mac on Nushan Kodikara</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 06:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.nushankodikara.com/tags/mac/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Antivirus Softwares Damage Our Hard Drives</title>
      <link>https://www.nushankodikara.com/blog/how-antivirus-softwares-damage-our-hard-drives/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 06:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nushankodikara.com/blog/how-antivirus-softwares-damage-our-hard-drives/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This post is a theory I tested and got some decent results, you can&amp;rsquo;t find any evidence about is this a thing, because the anti-virus industry is a huge pile of money and if someone speaks against it, they quickly take it down and then no one can see this. But from time to time, there are articles surfacing with the same issue and again the somehow takes it down for no reason.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Password Managers 2020</title>
      <link>https://www.nushankodikara.com/blog/best-password-managers-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 06:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nushankodikara.com/blog/best-password-managers-2020/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Password managers are pieces of softwares which keep our passwords saved in somewhere to decrease the chances of forgetting them and resetting, some password managers also can auto fill data and sync between platforms for the user&amp;rsquo;s convenience. Today, we&amp;rsquo;re discussing about password managers, are they safe to use? what kinds of password managers we have and how to use them safely. So without further explanation, Let&amp;rsquo;s get in to the post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Download Youtube Videos 2020</title>
      <link>https://www.nushankodikara.com/blog/download-youtube-videos-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 16:25:57 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nushankodikara.com/blog/download-youtube-videos-2020/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Let&amp;rsquo;s be real, We need to download Youtube Videos for so many reasons, Maybe mp3 from youtube, And we still don&amp;rsquo;t have a clear way, But today I&amp;rsquo;m here to change that, I Found some interesting apps and websites which can download From youtube directly as video or Audio. Without much details, Let&amp;rsquo;s dive in.
Android For android devices, I Have an app for you. This isn&amp;rsquo;t Available on playstore because that&amp;rsquo;s how it is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ultimate Adobe Softwares List With Universal Crack 2020</title>
      <link>https://www.nushankodikara.com/blog/adobe-softwares-ultimate-list-with-crack-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 15:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nushankodikara.com/blog/adobe-softwares-ultimate-list-with-crack-2020/</guid>
      <description>Introduction We all have used adobe software in some point of our lives and wandered how many others there are to explore. While none of the internet has a proper guide on this topic, I managed to create a complete solution for this case. and I Made a Universal crack for all adobe softwares. If you came for the crack itself.
Adobe Universal Crack (Windows / Mac) Download
You can crack up-to CC 2020 Adobe softwares from this crack and Rest of us, Let&amp;rsquo;s explore the options.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
