<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Windows on Nushan Kodikara</title>
    <link>https://nushankodikara.com/tags/windows/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Windows on Nushan Kodikara</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 06:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nushankodikara.com/tags/windows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Antivirus Softwares Damage Our Hard Drives</title>
      <link>https://nushankodikara.com/blog/how-antivirus-softwares-damage-our-hard-drives/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 06:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nushankodikara.com/blog/how-antivirus-softwares-damage-our-hard-drives/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This post is a theory I tested and got some decent results, you can&amp;rsquo;t find any evidence about is this a thing, because the anti-virus industry is a huge pile of money and if someone speaks against it, they quickly take it down and then no one can see this. But from time to time, there are articles surfacing with the same issue and again the somehow takes it down for no reason.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Password Managers 2020</title>
      <link>https://nushankodikara.com/blog/best-password-managers-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 06:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nushankodikara.com/blog/best-password-managers-2020/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Password managers are pieces of softwares which keep our passwords saved in somewhere to decrease the chances of forgetting them and resetting, some password managers also can auto fill data and sync between platforms for the user&amp;rsquo;s convenience. Today, we&amp;rsquo;re discussing about password managers, are they safe to use? what kinds of password managers we have and how to use them safely. So without further explanation, Let&amp;rsquo;s get in to the post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git Hub Version Control for Starters</title>
      <link>https://nushankodikara.com/blog/git-hub-version-control-for-starters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 06:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nushankodikara.com/blog/git-hub-version-control-for-starters/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Now let&amp;rsquo;s take an start on our project directories, we as programmers and developers, always run into certain problems regarding our folder structures, corrupted files, need to undo but unable to do that because we made a terrible mistake and so on. Is there a way which we can solve this? Yes it is! that&amp;rsquo;s called version controlling, Here we&amp;rsquo;ll be able to backup our codes with version numbers and retrieve anytime we want, and when working with several developers in a single project, we&amp;rsquo;ll be able to collaborate and code the same project simultaneously with these things, so without much explanation let&amp;rsquo;s get into it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Download Youtube Videos 2020</title>
      <link>https://nushankodikara.com/blog/download-youtube-videos-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 16:25:57 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nushankodikara.com/blog/download-youtube-videos-2020/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Let&amp;rsquo;s be real, We need to download Youtube Videos for so many reasons, Maybe mp3 from youtube, And we still don&amp;rsquo;t have a clear way, But today I&amp;rsquo;m here to change that, I Found some interesting apps and websites which can download From youtube directly as video or Audio. Without much details, Let&amp;rsquo;s dive in.
Android For android devices, I Have an app for you. This isn&amp;rsquo;t Available on playstore because that&amp;rsquo;s how it is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create an Eco System With Join by joaoapps</title>
      <link>https://nushankodikara.com/blog/create-an-eco-system-with-join/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 12:19:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nushankodikara.com/blog/create-an-eco-system-with-join/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Let&amp;rsquo;s be real, We all like to work in one place but access all of our devices, Apple has a solution for this but what if you don&amp;rsquo;t have an apple eco system? Today, Let&amp;rsquo;s discuss how we can create an ecosystem for with what we have and for a little price to pay, With Join by joaoapps.
There are more services like this, Push bullet is one of them but their prices are, for my tastes, unfair.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ultimate Adobe Softwares List With Universal Crack 2020</title>
      <link>https://nushankodikara.com/blog/adobe-softwares-ultimate-list-with-crack-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 15:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nushankodikara.com/blog/adobe-softwares-ultimate-list-with-crack-2020/</guid>
      <description>Introduction We all have used adobe software in some point of our lives and wandered how many others there are to explore. While none of the internet has a proper guide on this topic, I managed to create a complete solution for this case. and I Made a Universal crack for all adobe softwares. If you came for the crack itself.
Adobe Universal Crack (Windows / Mac) Download
You can crack up-to CC 2020 Adobe softwares from this crack and Rest of us, Let&amp;rsquo;s explore the options.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VS Code for Web Developers</title>
      <link>https://nushankodikara.com/blog/vs-code-for-web-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 07:38:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nushankodikara.com/blog/vs-code-for-web-developers/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Visual studio code is a powerful and a user-friendly code editor, It has extended functionality, which makes it an all-in-one solution for most of the web developers and This would be a follow up guide to a Web and Hybrid app development course I&amp;rsquo;m planning forward to.
Installation VS Code is available for Windows, Mac and linux, so pretty much It&amp;rsquo;s a cross platform code editor. one of my favourite.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Budget Online Radio Station Guide 2020</title>
      <link>https://nushankodikara.com/blog/budget-online-radio-station-guide-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2020 08:47:08 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nushankodikara.com/blog/budget-online-radio-station-guide-2020/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Youtube is the main source of entertainment these days, but people still want to enjoy radio streams for no reason, online radio stations are costy and it&amp;rsquo;s nearly impossible for a normal person to start an online radio station without getting in to any of the top stupid costing radio stream services. In this article, let me show you how I made an online radio station without wasting a single penny, or without sacrificing the quality</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Media Players 2020</title>
      <link>https://nushankodikara.com/blog/best-media-players-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 15:59:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nushankodikara.com/blog/best-media-players-2020/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this post, I would like to present to you with the best media players according to technologies they use. This is a weird post to make in this time period but I&amp;rsquo;m creating this as a follow-up for a new post I&amp;rsquo;m planning to post in the future about Online Radio Broadcasting Technologies.
What I&amp;rsquo;m Considering Here Well, While I&amp;rsquo;m Preparing the list, I was considering about several features to back it up with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows 10 Speedup Registry Tweaks</title>
      <link>https://nushankodikara.com/blog/windows-10-speedup-registry-tweaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 10:12:44 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nushankodikara.com/blog/windows-10-speedup-registry-tweaks/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Windows based PCs have a registry system to take control over the system wide operations and most of the times windows default operations are useless to most of us and somewhat annoying. So to be cleared, I made this easy to install Registry file to speed up your PC in matter of seconds.
What Does It Do? Well, here comes the boring part. If you don&amp;rsquo;t want to know what this file does to your PC, just skip this section and use the link below to download the program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Package Manager for Windows [ Chocolatey ]</title>
      <link>https://nushankodikara.com/blog/the-package-manager-for-windows-chocolatey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nushankodikara.com/blog/the-package-manager-for-windows-chocolatey/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Do you ever thought about a single command to install, uninstall or update softwares in Windows? How about a script automatically do everything for you? Guess what, you&amp;rsquo;re in the perfect place!
Chocolatey is a package manager for Windows, which you can install by a single command and do everything with a single command!
Showcase Install softwares
&amp;gt; choco install vlc  Updated softwares
&amp;gt; choco upgrade vlc  Uninstall softwares</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
